#### candidate profile from



David Charles Petty | PO Box 400222 | Cambridge, MA 02140-0003 USA Home Phone: +1.617.331.2345 | Email: dcp@alum.mit.edu | Candidate ID# 01146677

## **Professional Objective**

To secure a position at a dynamic technology company where my skills and experience in product design, engineering management, and business development can best be used.

#### **Summary of Qualifications**

The Candidate has worked in telecommunications product and software design since 1980. From 1996–2003 he worked as an engineer and manager at the world's leading speech-recognition software company. For Dragon Systems, L&H, and ScanSoft, the Candidate led company efforts in over-the-telephone speech transcription. Most recently he managed the AudioMining group in developing revolutionary products that use Dragon Systems' best-of-breed speech-recognition technology to render recorded audio and audio-video media searchable.

The Candidate was a founder of two telecommunications industry start-ups — Telelogic and digiTel. Telelogic delivered over 400,000 trunk-side autodialers with his software to MCI, Sprint, and the other top interexchange carriers. For digiTel, and as an independent consultant, the Candidate worked on telecommunications products for the Norwegian and Swedish PTTs, Siemens, and the manufacturer of the Telelogic dialer. His roles included directing engineering, providing architecture and product design, managing consultants, and effecting liaison with off-shore manufacturing companies in Asia. The Candidate was also instrumental in developing a line of physician-answering-service systems for Ring Medical — now the nation's largest provider of medical communications services, NotifyMD.

Throughout his career, the Candidate has compiled a strong record of product development and engineering management in real-time embedded systems, telephony, and automatic speech recognition. His teams have uniformly been characterized by timely delivery of high-quality products. He has been an innovator in applying cutting-edge software development techniques to product design — including the use of Forth, SDL, and Python. The Candidate has a Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering from the Massachusetts Institute of Technology.

Terms of Use: This proprietary information is disclosed subject to the Terms of Use at www.epronet.com/client/support/terms\_of\_use.asp, which are deemed accepted by any use, including contacting candidates. Unauthorized use of this information may subject you to liability for civil sanctions. Further distribution is prohibited. Hiring the candidate identified herein will require payment of a fee to eProNet as specified in the Terms of Use.

August 25, 2003 www.epronet.com page 1



#### **Work History**

# MassBay Consulting, LLC | Cambridge, MA USA | March 2003 - Present Managing Director

Co-founded startup consulting company developing software-based voice products for wireless broadband devices used by businesses and consumers. Held position of Managing Director.

# Dragon Systems / Lernout & Hauspie / ScanSoft | Waltham, MA USA | July 1996 - February 2003

#### Director of Development, AudioMining™

- Held position of Director of Development, AudioMining<sup>™</sup>. Directed development of AudioMining<sup>™</sup> product line, including successful release of four products per year. Supervised work of ten developers and co-directed product group.
- Held position of Manager, Telephony Development. Managed efforts in over-the-telephone speech recognition applying dictation engine to telephony systems & services. Supervised work of four engineers.
- Held position of Senior Telephony Engineer in Portable Products Group. Developed distributed, embedded automatic speech recognition system. Computer languages used: Python, C++, Java, UML.

† On 2000 June 7, Dragon Systems was acquired by L&H. On 2002 March 18, L&H was acquired by ScanSoft.

## Ring Medical, Inc. | Billerica, MA USA | 1992 - 1996 Senior Software Designer

Held position of Senior Software Designer. Co-developed companies line of hospital answering service systems, including integration with Nortel Meridian and Rolm switches. Company has since become the "nation's largest provider of medical communications services, NotifyMD." Computer languages used: C, SDL, Perl.

#### N/A | Cambridge, MA USA | 1989 - 1991 Independent Consultant

- Developed and distributed software upgrade for trunk-side autodialer to accommodate major changes in North American Numbering Plan for Cambridge Software Project, Inc., Cambridge MA.
- Redesigned and maintained answer detection system for Homisco, Inc., Melrose MA.
- Designed and implemented digital electronics and software for Siemens videotex decoder infrared keyboard for digiTel, Inc., Cambridge MA.
- Developed dual cable broad band network tester in conjunction with ASAtech, Inc., Pelham NH.
- Adapted trunk-side autodialer software for combination telephone and cable television service for Twixtel Technologies, Inc., Framingham MA and GEM Electronics, Inc., Chicago IL.

## digiTel, Inc. | Cambridge, MA USA | 1986 - 1988 Director of Engineering

Helped found product development company. Held position of Director of Engineering. Oversaw development of TEX family of videotex decoders, including customized versions for the Norwegian

Terms of Use: This proprietary information is disclosed subject to the Terms of Use at www.epronet.com/client/support/terms\_of\_use.asp, which are deemed accepted by any use, including contacting candidates. Unauthorized use of this information may subject you to liability for civil sanctions. Further distribution is prohibited. Hiring the candidate identified herein will require payment of a fee to eProNet as specified in the Terms of Use.

#### **David Charles Petty**



and Swedish PTTs. Effected manufacturing liaison of authentication tokens for AITRC. Wrote product and design specifications, designed product software and electronics, managed all project phases, and effected manufacturing liaison with North American and Asian companies. Supervised work of eight consultants.

#### Telelogic, Inc. | Somerville, MA USA | 1980 - 1985 Associate Director of Research and Development

Helped found telecommunications manufacturing company. Co-designed company's major product line, trunk-side autodialers, of which there were 400,000 in use. During my employment, Telelogic grew from five employees to over 350 and was valued at \$50 million. Held positions of Senior Software Designer, Dialer Engineering Manager, Computer Systems and Tools Manager, and Associate Director of Research and Development. Worked extensively with Forth development environment for product design and tool design. Designed and oversaw development of cross-compilers and assemblers for various microprocessors and minicomputers. Developed software documentation and control system. Developed VAX/VMS based company-wide computing facility. Worked with manufacturing engineers on product manufacturability and test fixture design. Worked with customers on product acceptance. Was hiring manager, supervising a group of ten engineers and staff.

#### **Education History**

BS Electrical Engineering, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 1986

#### **Professional Organizations**

- Member of ACM & IEEE.
- Founding participant in Knowledge Home initiative.
- Former Member of Board of Directors of Forth Interest Group. Member of ANS X3J14 technical sub-committee for standardization of the Forth development environment. Also member of Forth Standards Team, precursor to X3J14 and promulgator of FORTH-83. Ten-year participant in Forth Modification Laboratory. Six-year participant in Rochester Forth Conference.

#### **Publication History**

1984 May 8 | United States Patent No. 4,447,676 | Automatic dialer for telephone network access control.